# Rashmi AP

# Front-end Web Developer

Experienced front-end developer with 3.5+ years in developing and managing responsive and elegant web apps with a demonstrated history of working in the tech start-up space. Skilled in ReactJS, HTML and CSS. Strong engineering professional with a Bachelor's Degree focussed in Computer Science from B.M.S. College of Engineering.

$\geq$	rashmiap.10@gmail.com
	+91-9844869611
Q	Bengaluru, India
<b>•</b>	rashmiap.me
in	nkedin.com/in/rashmiap
	github.com/rashmiap

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Senior Software Engineer**

AmyGB.ai 🗷

11/2018 - Present

Bengaluru, India

AmyGB specialises in developing products in the area of Text & Vision for an enterprise using machine learning

- Designed and implemented an Express/NodeJS micro service REST API for AmyGB sales website that handles creation, updates and retrieval of data on MongoDB. AWS SES was used to send transactional emails to requested end users.
- Responsible for development and delivery of the complete front-end of products like Mail ERA, Vision ERA and KB Bot.
- Developed several quick web apps within short timelines for multiple client requirements, POCs and trade shows.

### **Software Engineer**

Roundglass ZoojooBE 🗷

01/2016 - 10/2018

Bengaluru, India

ZoojooBE is a game based social wellness platform that unites the workforce to form healthier habits.

- Being a small tight-knit team, I got a chance to wear many hats, from requirement analysis to generating the build.
- Worked closely with Product Managers, UX Designers and Backend Engineers to develop pixel perfect User Interface.
- Worked on various features on the App like Social feed, Dare, Pregnancy module and Journey which were developed using ReactJS on the frontend stack.
- Developed and maintained front-end of the sales website.

# **Associate IT Analyst**

Caterpillar Inc.

08/2015 - 12/2015

Bengaluru, India

Caterpillar is the world's leading manufacturer of construction and mining equipments, industrial gas turbines and diesel-electric locomotives.

 Being part of Caterpillar's Global Information Services(GIS) division, features required me to work across the mainframe stack with COBOL, the primary mainframe programming language which compiles to machine language, ISPF and JCL.

### **EDUCATION**

# **BE, Computer Science and Engineering** B M S College of Engineering, Bangalore

09/2011 - 05/2015

CGPA - 9.12 (out of 10)

 Treasurer, Fine Arts Club, 2014

### SKILLS



### **PROJECTS**

### Email Automation Tool (02/2019 - Present)

- Mail ERA is an intelligent, self-learning end-to-end mail management tool that bridges the gap between mailbox and CRM using NLP capabilities.
- It reads through e-mails, processes content, categorises them as per business use cases and generates auto-response suggestions to the majority emails.
- Developed a mobile responsive application with ReactJS, Material-UI, MobX and being a real-time app, leverages the usage of WebSockets to fetch real-time email conversations.

### Vision ERA OCR Platform (03/2019 - 04/2019)

- Vision ERA platform uses OCR technologies to extract relevant data from printed documents such as government ID cards and invoices while automating a significant amount of cognitive work.
- Developed the front-end using HTML5 Canvas with ReactJS, Material-UI and MobX.
- The uploaded document is mapped onto the canvas which shows the highlighted co-ordinates by hovering over the extracted data and also allowing users to extract a snippet by selecting the mouse over the area.

### Knowledge Base Bot (05/2019 - 06/2019)

- Knowledge Base portal is used to create, organise, search and share any content such as pdf, docs, images, videos internally by admins and agents of an enterprise.
- Some features of the platform include versioning documents, designing quizzes for a document and generating built-in reports for quizzes, documents and agents activity.
- Developed the front-end of the portal in ReactJS using Material-UI for CSS and MobX for state management.

### Social Stream (07/2018 - 08/2018)

- Social feed is a feature on the Zoojoobe platform that leverages on the social behaviour within the corporate.
- It allows users on the platform to share media that keeps them motivated to do a certain task.
- Like all other social feeds, Social Stream also has social elements like liking, sharing, commenting, tagging, subscribing to a particular post and so on.
- Developed using ReactJS and draft-js-plugins, a react plugin architecture for Facebook's Draft.js which includes emojis, mentions and stickers.